Steven Van Court, CIA

Coon Rapids, MN 55448

Phone: 715 - 864 - 0930 | Email: <u>Steven.vancourt@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-vancourt-cia-08375263/

GitHub: https://github.com/StevenVC-P | Portfolio: https://steven-vancourt.herokuapp.com/

Summary:

Self-starting and resourceful Full Stack Developer with military and audit experience. With training in implementing front-end and back-end coding, I am astute and always-learning. On group projects, I brought focus to design for user interactions on websites and databases. My experience helped me understand website functionality, coding for multiple platforms, and meticulously create fully functional code. From past experiences I can communicate clearly with others, both technical and non-technical team members, and promote drive towards end-user needs.

Technical Skills:

Languages: HTML, CSS, ES6 Javascript, Handlebars

Frameworks/Libraries: Node.js, Express, React, Jquery, Bootstrap

Tools: MySql, MongoDB, Rest APIs, Axious, Sequelize

Methods: Restful WebServices, Testing, Asynchronous Programming, Pair Programming

Projects:

Modern Mornings - Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, HTML5, APIs,

Summary: News and Reddit search site with a flexible SPA UX design for Mobile or PC, using API calls to Gnews.lo, quoteblock, and Reddit.

Technical Responsibilities: Set up API call to Gnew.lo, styling news cards, and building a display carousel **Professional Responsibilities:** Led two in a group project, providing both direction and assessing team skill sets

Daycare CRM - Technologies: JavaScript, PDFKit, AJAX, SQL

Summary: CRM system for daycare providers to track family information

Technical Responsibilities: Designed invoice with PDFkit and used javascript to create it dynamically **Professional Responsibilities:** Provided overall concept, scope, and determined necessary technologies

Swap - Technologies: React Framework, Bootstrap, Axios, Rest APIs, Mongoose

Summary: High quality social media platform for the zero energy swap enthusiast.

Technical Responsibilities: Created the base components, and the functionality of the comments and filter bar. **Professional Responsibilities:** Provided leadership, handled role assignments, and short term deadlines.

Professional Experience:

Internal Auditor Jun 2019 – Jan 2021

Christopher & Banks Plymouth, MN

· Assessed controls over financial reporting, and designed flow charts for financial controls

Consultant Auditor Oct 2018 - May 2019
Wipfli Minneapolis, MN

- Collaborative fast-paced team for one week assignments with different local banks
- Reviewed banking compliance regulations, catching on average 10 issues per location visited

Volunteer Auditor Summers of 2018 – 2020 Hope Fellowship Ramsey, MN

Evaluated church's financial controls, resulting in 5 recommendations taken up by the board

Feb 2016 - Oct 2018 Minneapolis, MN

Tena Companies

· Analized loan portfolios, identified customer service issues resulting in retraining of staff.

Financial Specialist 247TH FIN. MINNESOTA NATIONAL GUARD

Feb 2006 – Feb 2012 Roseville, MN

Trainer/Mentor Jun 2010, Jun 2011

- Provided training and critique of payroll and disbursement processes at annual events **Deployed to Iraq** *Jul* 2007 *Mar* 2008
- Collaborated with a team of 5 analyzing and resolving 20-30 payroll and entitlement issues daily
- Identified 1,000 unauthorized benefit claims and corrected 2000 soldier's unclaimed benefits

Education:

Full Stack Developer - University of Minnesota Certificate - May 2021

 A fulltime 12 week intensive program focused on gaining programming skills in Javascript, Databases, and React Certified Internal Auditor – Certificate #159480 - Mar 2018 University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire - Sept 2010 - May 2013 Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.) Finance, General Eagle Scout Award - Sept 2005